Using the images to create a video and finally combine the audio with the video.
The images stages
For this stages, I, am using Comtypes library in Python to export each slide as a PNG file.
The prose is easy to use and the exported pictures are high solution.
The cons is this will online work on window and required user to install PowerPoint.
The audio stages
In this step, we actually have many different types of Python libraries to support the conversion.
At first, I tried Google TDS but the voice was very stiff, rough and fake.
After that, I learned about PyTDS, the male voice is quite good with many improvements such as light accents and being able to customize the reading speed.
However, I'd like to find a library with better support and a more human like voice.
I tried TDS library by CoQi.ai.
By using pre-trained AI models, it can create female voices with clear accents and punctuation.
After testing on a few models, I feel most satisfied with Tacotron 2DCA.
In addition, it also allows users to train their own AI, but that takes a lot of resources and time.
First, I used PPTX library to extract all speaker notes in each slide.
Then, using the AI model to convert texts into audio files.
Finally, we combine all of the audio files into a single one using audio segment library.
The video stages.
Using the MoviePy library, I am able to create separate clips with different duration for each images.
The duration is depended on the corresponding audio file.
Then, by combining all the clips, I get the full video.
Now, the final step is adding the full audio file into the video and save.
Thank you for listening.